multilingualarchive.com 2012-06-14

# WorldLingo Privacy Policy

Effective from 17th October 2008.

[](https://www.truste.org/ivalidate.php?url=www.worldlingo.com&sealid=102) _WorldLingo is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent organization whose mission is to build user's trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the Web site www.worldlingo.com. Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe._

_If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Victoria Pratt at[privacy@worldlingo.com](mailto:privacy@worldlingo.com). If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe at http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns._

  1. **EU Safe Harbor.**

WorldLingo, complies with the EU Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union. If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Victoria Pratt (privacy@worldlingo.com). If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concern.

  2. Dispute Resolution with WorldLingo. WorldLingo participates in the EU Safe Harbor Privacy Framework as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce. As part of our participation in the Safe Harbor, we have agreed to TRUSTe dispute resolution for disputes relating to our compliance with the Safe Harbor Privacy Framework. If you have any complaints regarding our compliance with the Safe Harbor you should first contact us (as provided above). If contacting us does not resolve your complaint, you may raise your complaint with TRUSTe by Internet at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>, fax at 415-520-3420, or mail at Watchdog Complaints, TRUSTe, 55 Second Street, 2nd Floor San Francisco, CA, USA 94105. If you are faxing or mailing TRUSTe to lodge a complaint, you must include the following information: the name of company, the alleged privacy violation, your contact information, and whether you would like the particulars of your complaint shared with the company. For information about TRUSTe or the operation of TRUSTe's dispute resolution process, see <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php> or request this information from TRUSTe at any of the addresses listed above. The TRUSTe dispute resolution process shall be conducted in English. For human resources data we have agreed to cooperate with Data Protection Authorities.
  3. WorldLingo. will fulfill your request to update, change or delete your personal information within 30 days by contacting Victoria Pratt ([privacy@worldlingo.com](mailto:privacy@worldlingo.com)).

Your privacy is of the uppermost importance to us. We take seriously our responsibility to keep your data safe and protected. To this end we adhere to the following principles:

  * We will not exchange or sell your personal data to third parties for any purpose.
  * We will not share your contact information with another user or third party without your express consent.
  * Any personal data that you provide will be secured with industry standard protocols and technology.

Notice of any changes that may affect your personal data or how it is used or shared will be posted in updates to our Privacy Policy online. We will notify you of any changes to the Privacy Policy via our website 30 days prior to the changes taking effect.

If you choose to continue to use WorldLingoservices after notice of changes have been sent to you or published on our site, you thereby opt into the new Privacy Policy and accept the changed practices.

WorldLingo' Privacy Policy is designed to help you understand how we collect and use the personal data you provide. Helping you make informed decisions when using WorldLingo products and services located at www.worldlingo.com and its directly associated domains (collectively, "WorldLingo" or "Website").

By using or accessing WorldLingo, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should contact our privacy staff at privacy@worldlingo.com.

* * *

## 1\. Information Collection and Use

In general, you can visit WorldLingo online without telling us who you are and without sharing any personal information. There are times however, when we will require information from you.

You may choose to give us personal information in a variety of situations. For example, you may want to give us information, such as your name and e-mail address enabling us to correspond with you, to process an order, or to provide you with a subscription service.

You may also provide us with your credit card details to purchase a service from us or a description of your education and work experience in connection with a vacancy at WorldLingo that you wish to be considered for. We intend to let you know how we will use such information before we collect it from you; if you tell us that you do not want us to use this information to make further contact with you beyond fulfilling your requests, we will respect your wishes. If you give us personal information about somebody else, such as a spouse or work colleague, we will assume that you have their permission to do so.

When you use any Machine Translation service provided by WorldLingo, whether it's via this website, Microsoft Office, a customer website or imbedded within a service, WorldLingo guarantees that it will never make nor keep a copy of your original text submitted for translation, neither will it make nor keep a copy of your translation results. 

## We collect your personal information by the following methods:

## 1.1 Registration

In order to become a WorldLingo user or future customer, you can create an account on this Website. To create an account you are required to provide the following contact information: first name, last name and email address. _A secure password containing letters and numbers maybe generated at random by WorldLingo; alternatively you will be able to choose your own password._

You have the option to provide us with demographic information such as preferred currency and gender; we encourage you to submit this information so we can provide you a more personalized experience on our site.

WorldLingois the sole owner of the information collected on WorldLingo's Web site.

## 1.2 Profile Information

When you become a user, you may provide additional information in the Manage My Account section of your account; selecting your preferred source and target language, your country of residence, preferred currency and time zone. Providing additional information beyond that which is required at registration is entirely optional, but enables us to provide you with an enhanced user experience as we can select appropriate values during servicing you; for example providing online payment for a translation project.

## 1.3 Orders

If you purchase a service from us, we request certain personal data from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (name, email and billing address) and financial information (credit card number and expiry date). We use this information for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use the details provided to contact you.

## 1.4 Log Files

We gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically collected data to personal data.

We use a third-party tracking service, Google Analytics that uses cookies to track non-personal data about visitors to our site to be able to gain demographic data about the location of our visitors and total number of users.

## 1.5 Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on the site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personal data you submit while on the site.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for the user to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when the browser is closed. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file.

We set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don't have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

If you reject cookies, you may still use the site, but your ability to use some areas of the site will be limited.

Some of our business partners (e.g. advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. See "Third Party Advertisers."

* * *

## This section covers the use of cookies by the site only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

## 1.6 Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

Our third party advertising partners may employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs). Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of one pixel. We do not link any information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information.

## 1.7 Uses of Information

The personal data you choose to provide on this site is used solely to enhance your experience of this site. Additional information, that does not personally identify you as an individual, "patterns of utilization" data is collected by the site, this information may be used by WorldLingo to identify market opportunities and to make service improvements as WorldLingo deems appropriate. Additionally "patterns of utilization" data may be shared with trusted third parties.

## 2\. Communications from WorldLingo

## 2.1 Special Offers and Updates

We may occasionally send you information about products and services, special deals, and promotions. Out of respect for your privacy, when you created your account you may opt out of these communications, additionally please see the "Choice and Opt-out" section.

## 2.2 Service-related Announcements

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email.

You may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature.

## 2.3 Customer Service

Based upon the personal data you supply us with at registration, we may send you up to two welcoming emails to verify your username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by email or telephone.

## 3\. Information Sharing and Disclosure

## 3.1 Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)

We share aggregated demographic information about our user base with our partners and advertisers. This information does not identify individual users. We provide reports to our advertisement partners about the number of users we have from specific countries. We do not link aggregate user data with any personal data.

## 3.2 Personally identifiable information

We DO NOT share personal data with Third Parties.

## 3.3 Agents

We use credit card processing companies to bill you for services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personal data for any purpose other than that for which it was originally intended.

## 3.4 Service Providers

We use contracted specialists to provide the professional human translation and DTP services advertised on our site. When you submit a human translation job any personally identifiable information contained in the translation will not be used for any purpose other than that for which it was originally intended. Any other personal data is not shared with the contractor(s) who provide that service.

These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose.

## 3.5 Legal Disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose your personal data as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or legal process served on our Web site/ Company.

## 3.6 Choice/Opt-out

We provide you the opportunity to ‘opt-out' of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a product/service but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference on our order form.

We post customer testimonials on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information such as the customer's name. We do obtain the customer's consent prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial.

## 3.7 Third Party Advertisers

The adverts appearing on the Web site are delivered to users by our advertising partners. We share aggregated Web site usage information about users with third party advertisers for the purpose of targeting advertisements on the site.

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). 

## 4\. Links to Other Sites

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by WorldLingo Please be aware that we, WorldLingo are not responsible for the privacy practices of other such sites.

We encourage you to be aware of this when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personal data.

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site.

## 5\. Access to Personally Identifiable Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer wish to use our service, you may correct and/or update it through the Manage My Account feature accessible when you sign into your account.

In the case of deactivating or canceling your account you may do this through the Manage My Account feature, however, if you have an active subscription or jobs pending you will not be able to deactivate or delete your account and must email Customer Support at [unsubscribe@worldlingo.com](mailto:unsubscribe@worldlingo.com).

## 6\. Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (credit card details) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can send email us at [security@worldlingo.com](mailto:security@worldlingo.com).

## 7\. Business Transitions

In the event WorldLingogoes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company or sale of all or part of its assets, your personal data will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

## 8\. Changes in this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to modify or change this Privacy Policy at any time. If we decide to change or modify our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes or modifications to this Privacy Policy. We will notify you of any changes to the Privacy Policy via our website 30 days prior to the changes taking effect.

## 9\. Contact Us

If you have any questions or comments please email us at [privacy@worldlingo.com](mailto:privacy@worldlingo.com) or contact us at:

WorldLingobr/> Attn.: Privacy policy issues  
6375 S Pecos Road, Suite #203  
Las Vegas, NV 89120
